你在十二个月的服刑期中
You've been good...
过去八个月内
...ish..behavior.
表现良好
In 8 of 12 months time served.
我们依照酌处权获准你假释
We have the discretion to grant parole,
五天后  本月十号星期五
Friday the 10th, five days from now.
你对你的所作所为心怀歉意吗
Are you sorry about what you did?
是的
Yes.
就一句"是的"吗
Yes?
那是正确答案  不是吗
That's the correct answer, isn't it?
你是想招我们烦吗
Are you trying to annoy us?
不  我只是想给你们
No, I'm just trying to give you
能保住你们饭碗的答案
the answers you need to cover your asses,
好让你们填完表格  然后放我出去
fill out your forms, and let me out of here.
我们需要你表现出悔恨
We need you to show us remorse.
我们的体制就是这样运转的啊
Is that how our system works?
释放最会演戏的犯人吗
Release the best actors?
真不敢想像那会造成怎样的后果
I shudder to think what that world would be like.
你开车撞进你前女友的家
You drove your car into your ex-girlfriend's house
然后在国外潜逃了三个月
and then fled the country for three months.
我知道她女儿在祖母家里
I knew that her daughter was at grandma's,
每周五都如此
like every Friday,
也看到所有人都去往客厅了
and I saw everyone else move into the living room.
他们可能会折回来的
They could've moved back.
我会注意到的
Which I would've noticed
因为我正开车冲向他们
since I was driving right towards them.
闭嘴  我们接到通知要缩减犯人数量
Shut up. We got an order to reduce overcrowding.
我就直说了  只要你对一名警卫出言不逊
But let me be clear-- you mouth off to one guard,
被我们发现你的牢房里有一只餐厅的托盘
we catch you with a single cafeteria tray in your cell,
违反任何我都记不清楚的规定
you break any rules I don't even remember,
你就得在这里再待足四个月
you can park your ass here for four more months.
且不说你是否悔恨
So forget being sorry.
你能安分守己过完这五天吗
Can you stay out of trouble for five days?
可以
Yes.
排队取药  阿索法
Get in line for meds! Asofa!
你为什么总是帮他啊
Why you keep helping him out?
好问题  为什么我要确认
Yeah, why would I wanna make sure
我的杀人犯狱友
that my homicidal cellmate
服用的是正确的精神抑制药
is taking the right anti-psychotics?
豪斯
House!
门德尔松
Mendelson!
他该服用八十毫克的普萘洛尔  这只有四十
He's on 80 mg of Propranolol. That's 40.
你是对的  抱歉
You're right. Sorry.
没关系
No worries.
我喜欢淘气小护士
I like my nurses naughty.
门德尔松  我开始觉得
I'm starting to think, Mendelson,
你就是喜欢我口水的味道
that you just really like the taste of my spit.
豪斯  看
Hey, House.
看看我们的新标志
Check out our new brand, huh?
门德尔松  你还真喜欢万字符啊
You really got a thing for swastikas, Mendelson.
不觉得讽刺吗
Like an ironic thing?
这是个德国名字
It's a German name.
豪斯也是  但我是犹太人
So is "House." I'm Jewish.
不  其实我是个黑皮肤的吉普赛同性恋
Nah, I'm a black, gay gypsy.
马进f3
Knight to King's Bishop three.
后进f7
Queen to King's Bishop seven.
你是豪斯  对吧
You're House, right?
我肘部有奇怪的痛感
I got these weird pains in my elbows
还有我的膝盖
and in my knees--
你知道吗  更奇怪的是
You know, what's weirder
诊室明明空间很大
is how the clinic is a large room
你却能把我当成它
and you somehow confused me with it.
虽然实话实说  我确实挺大只
Although, to be fair, I am large.
你好  罗诺
Hi, Rollo.
我意识到这可能是个反问句
I realize this is probably a rhetorical question--
你为什么要偷我的东西
Why are you stealing my stuff?
豪斯  听说你短期内就要出去了
Hey, House. I heard you're on short time.
你不需要这个了
You won't need this.
你听说我的假释了
You heard about my parole,
却没听说过我对偷我的金枪鱼的人
but not about my violent reactions
产生的暴力反应
when people steal my tuna.
放回去
Put it back.
没门儿
Nuh-uh.
真的吗
Really?
你在招惹一个
You're stepping to a guy
比你重五十磅
who outweighs you by 50 pounds,
还带着一根准许在监狱里使用的
and he was carrying a cane, which,
且插入你的结肠后
while prison-approved, would still cause some issues
仍会有不小伤害的拐杖
if inserted into your colon.
来啊  看你怎么搞砸自己的假释
Yeah, like you losing your parole.
你也不能告发我
And you ain't gonna rat me out neither,
因为你不会想背上打小报告的恶名
'cause you don't wanna get a snitch jacket
最后在洗澡的时候被人捅死
and wind up shanked in the showers.
所以你只能眼睁睁地看我走出去
So you're just gonna let me walk out of here.
你想报复这些家伙
You wanna get back at these guys...
那就在周五那天活着出去
Get out alive on Friday.
好了  豪斯  工作去吧
All right, now go to work, House.
你那一棋把我将死了  对吧
Oh, and that was Checkmate, right?
没错
Yep.
豪斯  我听说你短期内就能出狱了
I heard you're on that short time, House?
如果你想要金枪鱼  为时已晚
If you like tuna, you're a little late.
我想要你的立体声装备和头戴耳机
I want your stereo and your headphones.
我可以等你先做完你的工作
It can wait till you finish your work.
送到我的牢房里
Drop it off in my cell.
九十九点九
99.9.
我想先给他用头孢曲松治疗
I'm gonna start him on ceftriaxone.
很好
Good catch.
我说不定就会遗漏这点
I might've missed that.
那不是淋病
It's not gonorrhea.
我可没说是啊
I didn't say it was.
是没说出来
Not out loud,
但你觉得为关节疼痛
but you're figuring that joint pain,
加之高热和不健康的生活方式
plus fever, plus a low lifestyle
开头孢曲松的处方合情合理
equals a ceftriaxone prescription.
你是说我得了淋病吗
So you're saying I got the clap?
我才来这里一周
I've only been in here one week.
我女朋友也没病
My girlfriend's clean.
我在这里都没有女友
I ain't got a girlfriend in here.
你怎么知道头孢曲松的
How do you know about ceftriaxone?
豪斯以前是个医生
House used to be a doctor.
不再干这行了
Not going back,
你那震惊的表情既让我又荣幸又不快
and that look of shock is elitist and offensive.
医生也堕落  毕竟这里是美国
Doctors can be degenerates. This is America.
少量眉毛缺损
There's subtle eyebrow loss.
是狼疮
It's lupus.
他脸上没有其他斑疹
Well, there's no discoid or malar rash on his face.
如果他头够大的话就能看到了
Which would be dispositive if he was just a giant head.
他说得有道理
He's got a point,
但还是由你做决定
but I'll let you make the call.
根本没必要进行全身斑疹检查
No, there's no reason to search for a bodily rash
因为通常狼疮不会表现这样的症状
since lupus doesn't usually present that way.
"通常"
"Usually"?
我猜这对狱医来说足够了
Well, I guess that's good enough for prison work.
你们不会给胡说八道的犯人记一笔吧
You don't write people up for mouthing off, do you?
"通常"不会
Not usually.
别惹斯托普
You don't wanna mess with Stomper.
可不是因为他喜欢圣诞驯鹿
He didn't get that name
别人才那么叫他的
because he's a fan of Santa's reindeer.
你以为圣诞驯鹿
You think one of Santa's reindeer
有叫斯托普的吗
was called Stomper?
你没抓到重点
You're missing my point.
连圣诞驯鹿叫什么都搞不清  我才不要听你的
I'm not gonna listen to a guy who can't name the reindeer.
你也见到了迪亚兹在院子里的惨状
Well, you saw what happened in the yard with Diaz.
他还没说什么呢
He barely said a couple of words
他们就恼了
and set the boy off.
不是吧
Oh, no.
又是这副表情
I know that look.
你好  斯托普
Hey, Stomper.
我的东西呢
Where's my stereo?
我送到你屋里了
I brought it to your cell.
没在那
It ain't there.
我还没说完呢
I was just getting to that part.
罗诺尾随我  把它拿走了
Rollo followed me in and took it.
罗诺不敢对我那么不敬
No way Rollo'd diss me like that.
他敢啊  我可不想造谣  但是...
Way. I don't wanna start any rumors, but--
但是什么
But what?
他就说  "我可以扳倒斯托普"
Well, he was all, you know, "I could take stomper."
我就说  "何以见得"
And I was all, "How come?"
他就说  "瞧上个月
And he was all, "'cause of how Diaz
迪亚兹是怎么教训他的"
kicked his ass last month."
他其实管你叫"斯托皮"
In fact, he actually called you "Stompee,"
是"皮皮"哦
with an "ee."
我觉得他是想说...
I think his gist was...
你偷了我的立体声吗
You took my stereo?
出去  斯托普
Get out of my house, Stomper.
我没有立体声
I ain't got no stereo.
那这是什么
Well, then what's this, then?
什么  不是我放的
What? I didn't put that there!
你这个狗娘养的骗子  敢当着我面骗我
You're gonna lie to my face, you lying son of a bitch!
我什么都没做
What? I didn't do anything!
下次你的立体声我拿定了
Next time I will take your stereo!
那可真蠢
That was stupid.
你说的  是"聪明"的同义词吗
Is that, like, a synonym for "clever"?
等他们出了禁闭室
By the time they get out of solitary,
我已经在斐济大学教物理了
I'll be teaching physics at the University of Fiji.
你还有四天
You have four days left.
还有多少鬼把戏
How many more tricks do you got?
别
Don't.
新宠物吗
This another pet?
一定没有好下场
'Cause it's gonna end badly.
就像以前一样
Again.
记得我们讨论过这个吗
Remember we talked about this?
至少我有在说  你很诡异地看着我
At least I talked, and you stared at me eerily.
我觉得挺诡异的
I think it was eerily.
"诡异"感觉是个高级词汇
"Eerily" felt like the best-case scenario.
脱掉衬衫  让我找下疹子
Take off your shirt so I can find the rash.
你现在打算帮我了
Oh, now you wanna help me.
因为那个医生不信你吗
'Cause that doctor didn't believe you?
如果你有更好的办法
Well, if you can think of a better way
能证明她是个蠢蛋
to prove that she's an idiot,
我洗耳恭听
I'm all ears.
早查完早了事
Now, let's get this over with.
好吧
Yeah.
那是妮可
That's Nicole.
她现在和她妈妈一起住
She lives at her mom's now
因为她丢了工作
on account that she lost her job.
她妈妈恨我  所以她不能来探监
Her mom hates me, so she can't visit,
她也不能接我的电话
she ain't accepting my calls.
你交往的是个12岁的姑娘吧
Well, that's what happens when you date a 12-year-old.
你不信我吗
You don't believe me?
相信就意味着一定程度的在乎
Belief implies a level of giving a crap
这我可办不到
that I am never gonna achieve.
脱裤子
Pull down your pants.
不是我处心积虑要证明
It's not that I was trying to prove
你是个傻瓜什么的
that you're an idiot or anything,
但我今早和狼疮小伙去沙滩日光浴
But lupus boy and I were at the beach this morning,
发现他左大腿处有个疹子
and I noticed a rash on his left thigh.
我查了你的资料
I checked you out.
是个人物
You were a pretty big deal.
出什么问题了
What went wrong?
原因显而易见又了无生趣
Something very obvious and very boring.
嗑药吗
Drug related?
伪造处方吗
Forging prescriptions?
你真厉害
Oh, you're good,
如果你给狼疮小伙用泼尼松
just like lupus boy will be
他也会这么厉害的
when you start him on prednisone.
药名本来可以做有奖竞猜的
Name should've been a giveaway.
我会送他过来的
I'll send him up.
你怎么这么自信
Why are you so sure
我会听你的
I'm gonna do what you say?
因为你聪明  家底殷实  出身良好
Because you're a smart, old-money, trust-fund girl
你选择这份工作只是因为
who took this job because your liberal ideology
自由主义信念让你想与众不同
makes you wanna make a difference,
但你已经开始厌倦了
But you're already getting bored,
这有点意思
and this is interesting.
你为什么这么说
Why would you say any of that?
你穿的鞋
Your shoes--
每天都不同  每双都很贵
A different, expensive pair every day,
可从来不穿皮鞋
but never leather,
意味着你有钱又信奉自由主义
which means you're both rich and liberal.
戴着未被抛过光的古老金挂盒
Antique locket-- it's unpolished gold.
而不是时髦的吊坠
Not some hipster thing.
说明是传家宝  也就是你家底殷实
It's a family heirloom, which means old money.
奥斯勒  霍普金森医学院创建者之一
周五带奥斯勒围巾/领带是霍普金森传统
只在周五戴奥斯勒围巾
Osler scarf-- only on fridays,
说明你在霍普金森做的住院医
which means you did your residency at Hopkins,
也意味着你比我们上回交手所表现的
which means you're smarter than our interactions
要更聪明
would so far indicate.
至于你的眼睛
And your eyes--
你在这里的这三个月来
The only time you haven't looked bored
也就咱们讨论诊断时
in the three months since you've been here
你的眼神才略显生气
is when we've been discussing this diagnosis.
所以  对  你会按狼疮对他进行治疗
So, yeah, you'll treat him for lupus.
豪斯
House.
他找你
He wants you.
能假释出去了啊
Parole?
你怎么没告诉我
You didn't tell me.
我不想大家深情送别
I didn't want a big, emotional scene.
但规矩你懂的
But you know what the rules are.
日子不多了  就得提高税收
On short time, tax goes up.
你们要多少
How many do you want?
全部
All of 'em.
拜托  门德尔松
Come on, Mendelson.
我该每天服用六粒
I should be on six a day.
我自己留四粒  给你两粒
I get four, and I give you two.
好吧  熄灯后到我牢房再拿一粒
Fine. Get one in my cell after lights-out.
再加上周三  周四  周五
Plus Wednesday, Thursday, Friday,
一共十一粒
that's 11 in all.
我算的是二十粒
I count 20.
从周一算起  你周五走
You knew on Monday, you get out Friday.
一共五天
Five days.
你该早点告诉我的
You should've told me earlier.
他们一天只给四粒  马克斯
They give out four a day, Max.
你会有办法的
You'll figure something out.
你可有创造力了
You're a creative guy.
不如我弄个保护性拘留
What if I just go into protective custody,
在那破洞里度过这三天吧
spend the next three days in the hole?
你当然可以弄个保护性拘留啊
Oh, you could P.C. up.
但你之后就出去了
But then you'll get out,
不像你
and unlike you...
我在外面有不少好哥们
I got friends on the outside.
送货的
Porter.
医生  你要啥
Doc, what ya need?
我这周提供烤乳酪特惠
I'm running a special on grilled cheese this week.
还有些新的美女杂志
Got some new girly mags too.
我想要点
I was thinking of something more...
维柯...丁
Vicodin-y.
最少十六粒
At least 16,
周五中午前就要
and I need them Friday at noon.
这可得花不少钱
I mean, that's pricy,
但还是可以搞定的
but it can be done.
你让你外面的伙计
How about you have one of your peeps on the outside
给我在特伦顿的小弟寄200块怎么样
send $200 to my boy up in Trenton?
我没有伙计
I am peep-less.
你是在讨价还价吗
This is just you haggling, right?
不是  你有见过我打电话
No. You ever see me chatting on the phone,
接待访客吗
taking visitors?
那好吧  但你所有的东西都归我
All right, but I'm gonna have to clean you out.
我要你的金枪鱼罐头
I'm gonna need to see some tuna.
要你的邮票  立体声
I'm gonna need to see some stamps, uh, stereo--
你就尽快给我把货弄来吧
Just get 'em to me as soon as you can.
怎么了
What happened?
我想打个电话
I was trying to use the phone.
只是被挤了下  就这样
I just--I just got jostled a little, that's it.
谁打的你
Who hit you?
我只是碰了下墙
I just--I just bumped into the wall.
这不是狼疮
That's not lupus.
这是好消息吗
Is that good?
你现在感觉好吗
Does it feel good?
病了
Sick.
不是  我只是有点戒毒症状
No, I'm just going through a bit of withdrawal.
我在努力每天只服一粒药
I'm trying to survive on one a day
撑过最后几天
for the next few days.
不是说你
No.
救救他
Fix him.
不是狼疮  他手臂断了
It's not lupus. He broke his arm.
或者就是狼疮  只是他打了一架
Or it is lupus, and he was in a fight.
他只是被挤了下
He was in a jostle.
因为如果他承认打架
'Cause if he admits he was in a fight,
就得被关禁闭
then he goes to the hole.
他会这样骗狱警
That's why he'd lie to the guards.
但没理由骗我
He's got no reason to lie to me.
看见没  这眼神又出现了
See? There are those eyes again.
有可能是病毒感染症状
How about a viral syndrome,
或是耐甲氧西林金黄色葡萄球菌
or MRSA?
不对  骨损害不应这么早就出现
No, that wouldn't chew up the bone that fast,
医源性反应倒有可能
but reaction to meds could.
-我能  -能什么
- May I? - May you what?
能让我因给你看病历而被炒鱿鱼吗
Make me lose my job by showing you a patient file?
你不妨假设
But why don't you assume
他近期没有接受药物呢
no recent meds?
鉴于他的手指都被烟都熏黄了
How long can I assume that he's been smoking,
我可以假设他抽烟多久了呢
based on his yellow fingers?
你认为是肺癌吗
You're thinking lung cancer.
转移性的  我周五给他拍X光
Metastatic. I'll x-ray him on Friday.
我们和其它两个诊所
We share a traveling x-ray machine
共用一台移动式X光机
with two other clinics.
我周五就离开这里了
I'm out of here on Friday.
又不是他走
He's not.
要不这样吧
Well, how about...
要是他血栓脱落导致中风
if he throws a clot and strokes out,
你就用那X光机给他做尸检
you can use the x-ray to do the autopsy.
开始让他使用抗凝药物
Start him on blood thinners.
你行医的方式真挺有趣
Very interesting practice you must've run.
不需要检测
No need for tests.
不需要证据
No need for proof.
你去哪
Where are you going?
去搞证据
To the proof store.
关于妮可  你是对的
You were right about Nicole.
是说我一点都不在乎吗  我也赞同
About me not caring? I thought so.
问题不在于她妈妈  而是她
It wasn't her mom. It was her.
她不想和我说话
She doesn't wanna talk to me.
求你别说了  我在听你肺里的声音
Please, I'm trying to listen to your lungs,
不是你的自艾自怜
not your self-pity.
你的癌症可以先等等
Cancer can wait.
你这是要去院里转转吗
Hey, heading out to the yard?
能帮我弄只蟋蟀吗
You mind trying to find me a cricket?
想调包是吗
The ol' swap trick?
你不觉得  当你狱友发现
You don't think that will piss off your cellie even more
那是另一只虫子时  他只会更生气吗
when he figures it's a different bug?
我会把它们打扮的一模一样  真假难辨
I'll dress 'em the same, like in vertigo.
我试试  但他们喷了那么多的农药
Well, I'll try, but they spray so much pesticide.
我们还能活着就挺神的了
I'm surprised we're alive.
有道理
Good point.
那事儿能成吗
Hey. How's it coming?
不行啊
It ain't.
伙计们要纹新纹身
The confederates be giving themselves spankin' new tats.
我所有的维柯丁他们都要了
They putting a claim on all of my Vicodin.
老兄  我挺喜欢你的
Now, I love you and all, my brother.
不过我还是更喜欢
But not as much as I love my gang
我那群疯狂的纳粹兄弟
of crazy, roided-out nazi bitches.
往左边一英寸
Turn to an inch to the left.
听出差别了吗
Hear the difference?
是的
Yeah!
这叫做声影
It's called an acoustical shadow.
说明他有个肿瘤
It means he's got a tumor.
没有听诊器你是怎么听出来的
How did you find that without a stethoscope?
我不知道你还会这套啊
I didn't even know you could do this!
给他服用抗凝药物吧
Start the blood thinners.
我真得癌症了吗
So I for sure got lung cancer?
-没有  -是的
- No. - Yeah.
你只证明了
All you've proven
他的肺部有异物
is there's an anomaly in his chest.
说明你原先的诊断
Which means your initial diagnosis
有可能是对的
could still be right.
你对这点很不满意啊
Which apparently really bugs you.
我可以做个凝血功能检测
I could do a clotting test.
这...
That's...
这是个好主意
That's a good idea.
我们要在你耳垂上取点血样
We're just gonna cut your earlobe a bit
两分钟后回来检查
and check back in two minutes.
如果还有血渗出  那是正常现象
If there's a little blood bubbling up, that's normal.
如果完全凝结了
But if it's completely clotted,
就有可能是癌症
It may indicate cancer.
好吗  开始了哦
Okay? Ready?
你真的放弃行医了吗
Are you really leaving medicine?
那你准备从事什么行业呢
What are you gonna do?
你知道  对于一个
You know, for someone
向我求助过那么多次的人来说
who asks as many favors as you do,
你倒是丝毫没有费力气
you sure don't make any effort
讨好过我
to win me over.
在我念医学院之前
Before I went to med school,
我想过要成为物理学博士
I thought about getting a PhD in physics.
你听说过暗物质吗
You ever heard of dark matter?
通过星系旋转及宇宙运行的方式
The way galaxies rotate, the motion of the universe,
可以判断暗物质的质量
it means there's six times more stuff
是已知物质的六倍
than we can detect.
但这只是个理论
But it's theorized.
还没人证明过暗物质的存在
No one's ever proved it exists.
你想要研究暗物质
So you wanna research it?
原因呢
Why?
这是现存的最大谜题
It's the greatest mystery there is.
万物形成的理论
The theory of everything.
而且和人性完全无关
And completely divorced from humanity.
好吧  我与人性
Well, me and humanity.
水火不能相容
We got together too young.
你有天赋
Tsk. You have a gift.
你无法否认在这世上
There is something in this world
有些事是你非常擅长的
you are undeniably great at.
你很会观察人
You can read people.
你可以读懂他们
You-- you understand them.
你不能放弃行医
You gotta go back to medicine.
如果说就是这种天赋令我身陷囹圄
Well, if that gift is related to what brought me here,
你能理解我为什么不能回头了吧
you'll understand if I wanna check the returns policy.
血这么流是正常的吗
Is this supposed to happen?
有意思
Cool.
唧唧昨晚没怎么叫唤
Jiminy didn't chirp much last night.
如果它得的是病  那早就该挂了
If it's a disease, then he's six inches under.
但也有可能是杀虫剂中毒
But this could also be pesticide poisoning,
那就可以用苏打粉里的碳酸氢盐治疗
which bicarbonate of soda has been used to treat.
瞧好了
See?
这点就够了
Just so much and no more.
这会儿你应该说声"谢谢"
This is where you say "Thank you."
或者我说吧
Or I say thank you
谢谢你饶我一命
for not killing me.
谢谢
Thank you.
胸透没有看出有肿瘤
The x-ray didn't show any tumors.
那个声影只是个脂肪瘤
The acoustical shadow was just a lipoma.
我在想  你没事吧
I'm thinking-- You all right?
没事
I'm fine.
要布洛芬吗[常用止痛药]
Ibuprofen?
那没用的
That's not gonna help.
想看的话就看病人的病历吧
You can look at the patient file if you want.
你相信我吗
You trust me?
为什么不呢
Any reason I shouldn't?
你真的不会看人  是吗
You're really not good at reading people, are you?
还有地方
Or buildings.
人是很复杂的
People are complicated.
人也是会变的
And people change.
首先人并不怎么复杂
Not that much to the first,
其次人根本不会改变
and not at all to the second.
反正我能看病历就好
But if it'll get me the file...
如果把凝血功能异常算作症状之一的话
If we add "clotting disorder" to the symptoms,
肯定是中毒了
it's gotta be a toxin.
就他一个人出现了病症
This guy's the only one with symptoms.
毒源要么在他的牢房要么在他工作的地方
It's either gotta be his cell or his work station.
洗衣房
The laundry room.
可能是种溶剂或洗涤剂
So maybe a solvent or detergent?
你能陪我去取个样吗
Can you get me an escort to gather samples?
亚当斯医生
Dr. Adams.
他怎么拿着病历
Why does he have a file?
你得去弄些棉花棒
You need to get cotton swabs.
现在不行
But not now.
我有事要做
I got something to do.
现在是放风时间
You're a prisoner on tier time.
就是说  你没事要做
By definition, you have nothing to do.
我要给她家里  她朋友  她工作的地方打电话
Call her family, her friends, her work.
最终肯定能打通的
I'm gonna get through eventually.
你动作变慢了  人也虚弱了
You're moving slower. You're getting weaker.
你的病在侵蚀你的骨头  关节
This thing's attacking your bones, your joints,
和血液
your blood.
我女友更重要
Look, my girl's more important.
她不是你女友  你个傻瓜
She's not your girl, you idiot.
她曾经是
She was the girlfriend
找了你这么个失败的毒贩子
of a loser drug dealer.
你觉得她有自制力
Think she's got the self-control
傻等你三年吗
to wait around for three years?
你觉得她应该吗
You think she should?
我们被关在这里
There's a reason we're locked away
远离世人  是有原因的
from nice, normal people.
你外面的生活已经结束了
Your life outside is over.
你的朋友  爱人  同伴
Your friends, your girl, everyone you worked with,
他们已经继续生活
they've moved on.
滚出我的房间
Get out of my house.
滚出去
Get out!
赛克斯呢
Where's Sykes?
在其它诊所做兼职
Off at his other clinics.
很好  我要去检查洗衣房
Great. Well, I'm gonna go through the laundry.
给我点棉签
Give me some swabs.
不
No.
怎么  因为给我看病历他冲你嚷了
What? He yelled at you for letting me see the file?
你会想开的
You'll get over it.
做几年心理辅导
A few years of therapy--
关于入狱的原因  你为什么要说谎
Why did you lie to me about what you were in for?
好吧  事实上我开车冲进屋子
Okay, so I drove a car into a wall
而不是偷了些药片
instead of stealing some pills.
你明显不在乎我做过什么
You obviously don't care what I did.
而是介意我欺骗了你  伤了你的心
You care that I lied to you. You feel jilted.
我感觉自己好蠢
I feel stupid.
这  这根本说不通
It--it doesn't even make sense.
你为什么会坐牢
Why are you doing time?
你没有前科
You didn't have any priors.
也没有伤到任何人
You didn't hurt anyone.
我有个糟糕的律师
I had a bad lawyer.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我们不能再继续讨论这个病例了
We can't talk about this case anymore.
为让你明天能如期交药
We hear you're gonna need an incentive
我们听说你需要点鼓励
to get all my pills by tomorrow.
我没法凑齐二十粒  不过一旦我出去了
I--I can't get all 20, but once I get out--
你先出去
Give us a minute.
知道我为什么服丁螺环酮吗
Why do you think I'm on buspirone?
因为压力
The stress!
我差不多每天都拉肚子
And I get the runs almost every day.
一旦露出软弱迹象  一帮人就会排着队
Any sign of weakness, 20 guys would line up
把削尖的牙刷插到我眼睛里
to stick a sharpened-up toothbrush in my eye.
所以尽管我天性善良
So as much as my better nature
真的想给你开绿灯
really wants to give you a pass...
但那真的只会对我的健康不利
It just wouldn't be good for my health.
明天见
See you tomorrow.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
你还有火柴吗
You have any matches?
没有  那可是严重违禁品
No, that's serious contraband.
你在打什么算盘
What are you planning to do?
口香糖有吗
What about a stick of gum?
当然
Sure.
那个我也需要
I'm gonna need that too.
为什么
Why?
你问我为什么需要你一直带着
Why do I need the pen that you always carry around
却又从来不用的笔吗
and never write with?
这是B计划
This is plan "B."
你的脸怎么了
What happened to your cheek?
什么事
What is it?
着火
A fire?
豪斯  我们得撤离这里
House, we gotta evacuate this area.
快走
Come on.
豪斯
Hey. Hey, House.
你之前说我该怎么样来着
You were saying something about how I should, like,
呃  棉签什么
uh, swab or--
你又把我当成诊室了
You're confusing me with the clinic again.
什么
What?
你不管我了吗
You're abandoning me?
是的  就等你走开
As soon as you leave, I am.
为什么  有什么变化
Why? What changed?
我只是受够了
I'm just done.
不想管你  不想行医  不想治病
No you, no medicine, no fixing people.
受够了
Done.
现在出去
Now get out.
不
No!
你嘴唇肿大
Your lips are swelling.
张开嘴
Open your mouth.
你刚吃了什么吗
Did you just eat something?
烘肉卷  土豆  咖啡
Meatloaf, potatoes, coffee...
你对什么过敏吗
You allergic to anything?
警卫
Guard!
你将进入过敏性休克
You're going into anaphylactic shock.
警卫  该死
Guard! Dammit.
我得开个洞  让你能够呼吸
I gotta make a hole so you can breathe.
豪斯  离他远点
House, get away from him.
他出现过敏反应
He's having an allergic reaction.
无法呼吸
He can't breathe.
双手抱头  躺下
Lie on the ground with your hands behind your head.
阿尔瓦雷斯  看看我在做什么
Alvarez, look at what I'm doing!
气管切开术  拜托  伙计
It's a tracheotomy. Come on, man.
你知道我是医生
You know I'm a doctor.
他怎么了
What's wrong with him?
我也不知道
I have no idea.
PolyA  聚腺苷酸聚合酶
CRISTAL DISEASE  结晶病
SLE  系统性红斑狼疮  PAN  结节性动脉炎
SBE  亚急性细菌性心内膜炎
免于我俩受到私藏违禁品的指控
Saving us both from contraband charges.
很高兴能认识你
It was great knowing you.
我请求保护性监禁
I need to be taken into protective custody.
太棒了
That was great.
我想我真的已逃过一劫
I think I really dodged a bullet there.
你不需要保护性监禁了吗
You don't need P.C.?
呃  也不是什么私人恩怨
Uh, it's nothing personal.
我们再约  从长计议  我保证
We'll reschedule. Rain check, I promise.
不是因为食物  是因为热
It wasn't the food. It was the heat.
肥大细胞增生症
It's mastocytosis.
能被热液诱发
It can be set off by hot liquids,
像是他刚喝的咖啡
like the coffee he just drank.
肥大细胞增生症通常是皮肤病
Masto's usually a skin disease.
通常
Usually?
它会攻击任何器官
It can hit any organ.
关节痛  骨质减少  过敏反应
Joint pain, osteopenia, and anaphylaxis,
眉毛缺损
eyebrow loss...
症状符合
It fits.
有这个可能性
It's a possibility.
我会进行血液检查  谢谢
I'll run some blood tests. Thank you.
不  不
No, no!
靠血液检查确诊肥大细胞增生症
It's almost impossible to confirm masto
是不大可能的
with blood work.
给我五片阿司匹林
Just give him five aspirin.
如果他患有肥大细胞增生症
If he has masto,
就会陷入过敏性休克
he'll go into anaphylactic shock
再次不能呼吸
and won't be able to breathe again.
你明白"确认"一词的意思吧
You do understand the meaning of the word "Confirm."
我同意
I'll do it.
我差点儿死在监房里
I almost died in that cell.
豪斯  你之所以进来  就是因为你自以为
House, you're in here because you think you can do
可以随时随地为所欲为
whatever you want whenever you want.
你不能  我也不能
You can't, and neither can I.
我胆敢未经准许做实验性治疗
The A.C.L.U. would have my job,
公民自由联盟就会让我丢掉工作
my license, maybe even my house,
吊销我的行医执照  甚至让我失去房子
if I do an unauthorized experimental...
可如果真的是肥大细胞增多症
But if... if it is masto...
不是
It's not.
给他服阿司匹林能有什么害处
What do you have to lose by giving him the aspirin?
我不会冒这个险
I'm not taking the risk.
是他在冒险
It's his risk to take.
如果他再次发病
If he has another attack
牢房里又没有医生在  他会丧命
and there isn't a doctor in the next cell, he could die!
你就不能暂时放下自保
So for one second, will you stop covering your ass
试验一下吗
and do the test?
我认为豪斯是对的
I think House is right.
不行
No.
你个懦弱的白痴  我自己来
You're a moron and a coward. I'll do it myself.
警卫
Guard.
你在这里不受欢迎
You're done here,
就像你这辈子涉足的所有地方一样
just like every other place you've ever set foot in your life.
再让我在这里看见你
If I ever see you in here again,
我就报告上去
I will write you up,
让他们驳回你的假释
and they will revoke your parole.
豪斯医生
Dr. House.
你拿到足够的维柯丁了吗
Did you get all the vicodin you needed?
我不是傻瓜
I'm not an idiot.
那场火  你脸上的瘀伤
That fire, the bruise on your face...
我平时也跟犯人聊天  知道出门税的事情
I talk to prisoners. I know about exit taxes.
你明显是被人敲诈了
You're clearly getting squeezed.
我需要二十粒
I need 20.
还有  趁赛克斯不在
And let me back into the clinic
放我进诊室
when Sykes is gone.
我们会照顾好尼克的
We'll take care of Nick.
不用心怎么可能照顾好
You can't if you're not willing...
你顾好自己吧
Just take care of yourself.
干得好
Well done.
我就知道  你在这里就算学不会别的
If knew if you'd learned nothing else in here,
总能学会识时务者为俊杰
you'd learned the smart thing is to fall in line.
你说的再对不过了
You're absolutely right.
这里需要支援
I need backup here.
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
速度支援
you'd better be fast...
来呀  来呀
Come on. Come on!
多谢你送我进诊室
Thanks for getting me to the clinic.
干掉他
Take him out.
我还有两周就能出去了
I've got only two weeks left in my stretch.
干掉他
Take him out.
狱警  这边需要帮助
C.O.! We have a little problem here!
呼叫支援  呼叫支援
I need backup, I need backup!
阿尔瓦雷斯
Alvarez!
门德尔松  沙利文
Mendelson! Sullivan!
门德尔松  你会为此付出代价的
Mendelson! You're gonna pay for this.
哪里  我一个人在玩纸牌呀
Hey...I'm just playing solitaire.
双手放到脑后
Hands behind your head!
趴下
On the ground!
你真是幸运
You are so lucky.
有个人正被救护车送往普林斯顿综合医院
We got a guy in an ambulance heading to Princeton General.
还有十几个人被催泪瓦斯呛得死去活来
Another dozen getting teargas hosed off them.
坐下
Sit down!
阿司匹林在哪里
Where's the aspirin?
让开
Back off!
上帝呀
Oh, God.
难道你是故意挨揍的
Did you get beaten up on purpose?
豪斯  你在做什么
House, what are you doing?
豪斯  开门
House, open up!
这是直接命令
This is a direct order!
是啊  什么都是直接命令
Yeah, it's always a direct order.
八个月了  这里的命令就没有不直接的
Eight months. Haven't heard an indirect order in here.
亚当斯医生
Dr. Adams!
他们会驳回你的假释
They're gonna revoke your parole.
还会以新的罪名起诉你
They're gonna charge you with extra crimes.
你至少要再蹲上六个月监狱
You'll be here six more months, minimum!
抱歉  走神了  你说什么
Sorry. Distracted. You were saying?
我查过你的案卷  你不是没请到好律师
I checked your file. You didn't have a bad lawyer.
你根本没请律师
You had no lawyer.
没有申诉直接接受了处罚
You took the first deal they offered you,
因为你想要惩罚自己
because you wanted to punish yourself.
难道你认为挨一顿揍
Do you think getting beaten up,
救活一个病人就可以问心无愧了吗
you think saving this one guy will wipe your slate clean?
错
No.
那你为什么要这样
Then why are you doing this?
因为天生我才
'cause I have a gift.
你喝下这个
Once you drink this,
应该会立即发病
should get an attack almost immediately.
如果我的诊断无误的话  就是这样了
That is, if I'm right.
你平白给自己添了几个月刑期
Just bought yourself months in solitary.
这样值得吗
Was it really worth it?
如果我错了  那就不值
If I'm wrong, no, it wasn't.
不  不  抢下杯子
No! No! No! Get the cup!
抢杯子
Get the cup!
喝了它  快喝
Just drink it! Drink it!
不  抢下杯子
No! Grab the cup!
双手背后
Hands behind your back.
你刚才在想什么
What were you thinking?
我不知道  我一时害怕
I don't know. I--I was scared.
不
No!
你被炒了
You're fired.
不止是被炒了
You're beyond fired.
任何地方都不会再聘用你
You're completely unhireable anywhere.
明白我的意思吗
You understand that?
明白
Yes.
现在闭上嘴  看他会不会发病
Now shut up and let's see if he has an attack.
别急  再等一下
Come on, just a little more time.
带他出去
get him out of here.